Hmm? Hmm...
All these houseplants
just look the same to me.
What? Surely not.
Cactus... I want a cactus!
Why are you complaining?
You're the one who wanted some greenery
in the classroom for summer, Nene.
Whistle, whistle.
Say, Yamabuki-kun.
What's this one called?
That's a Ficus benghalensis.
Native to India's Bengal region,
it's also known as a banyan.
It's known for being long-living.
It's resilient and easy to raise,
so it's perfect for beginners.
But beware of the sap.
Gross! He's a plant otaku!
It causes allergic reactions,
so wear gloves when handling it.
Cactus...
Cactus... Cactus... Cactus...
Hey.
Cactus!
This one's pretty cute, no?
Cactus...
That's a pachira.
It's known for its five-leaf stems
and its rapid growth.
Cactus... Cactus...
Cactus...
During spring and summer in particular,
it'll grow a lot while you look away.
Cactus! Cactus!
Cactus...
We came to this faraway store
just to buy this one plant?
We picked it because
the five leaves represent us!
More like because it was cheap, right?
I wanted a cactus...
Sure is hot, though.
Summer's almost here, after all.
Ugh, I don't want to get sunburned.
I enjoyed the mini-concert the other day.
I really do love singing my own songs.
I want to pull off a street
performance the same way,
but I'm too scared to try.
Heck...
I still haven't managed to write a song.
What do I do? Summer break's almost here.
Rikka still hasn't brought me a new song.
Her trauma is deeper than I thought.
I should probably explore other options.
What can yours truly do?
Pretty much anything, that's what!
What the heck?
What's that sound?
Someone's doing a street performance.
I've never heard this song before.
Sorry, go on without me!
Huh?
What's going on, Rikka-chan?
Bathroom break?
I-I'm gonna be this tree's mommy?!
I've heard that hypnosis
can help one overcome trauma.
I'll ask my big sis to coach me.
It really is Aiko. I could tell
by the way she played.
So she's still doing this, huh?
I can't be seen because it'd be awkward,
but I want to stay and listen some more.
Thank you.
The next song will be my last.
Say, missy.
Nobody's even listening.
What's the point in continuing?
Uh-oh...
Shut your trap, moron!
I'm doing this because I want to!
Say what?
You're shit at this, so just quit!
Well, you've got shit for ears, asshole!
I'm not gonna put up with
anyone who insults my music!
You're never gonna make it anywhere! Pah!
Shut it, fool!
Never show me your face again,
you old fart!
Anyway, here's my last song.
I didn't write this song by myself.
I wrote it with a friend of mine
a long time ago.
We did music together
back in middle school.
We were so excited
when we finished the song,
thinking we made a masterpiece,
and we sent it to a record label.
We actually got a response, too.
Which one of you sang the chorus?
We only need the girl with that voice.
But I was still happy,
because our music had been acknowledged.
That's why I entrusted
everything to my friend.
I told her she'd better make it!
She'd better become the number one
artist in Japan with our music!
But what did that idiot do?
She had a setback or two
and ran away from the record label!
Quit chickening out and running
to covers of idol songs, you moron!
What kind of middle-schooler brat
gives up after one failure?!
So I have to keep singing this song.
After all, her talent is the real deal.
Even if she wasn't
Japan's number one artist,
she could still be number one
in someone's heart.
So it's fine as long
as somebody understands.
If you come to like this song,
please remember it.
"The Calm of Night."
As the sun sank into the sea
We let out a deep sigh
And the oceans responded to us
With a big white wave
And dragged the wind away with it
Keep watching this 5-yen coin,
and what do you know...
You'll find that even a lemon
can taste sweet like sugar
Ooh, I'm starting to believe!
Okay, go ahead and eat that lemon slice.
Sour!
Breathe in... breathe out.
My tongue...
It didn't work at all.
I was hoping to remove
Rikka's trauma this way!
Rikka's starting her mini-concert.
It's been a while since her last one!
Hello, everyone.
Thanks for coming
even though it's so hot.
Let's get right to it.
Here's the first song.
Wait, what's the title?
Wonder what she's gonna perform.
As the sun sank into the sea
What is that song?
Wait, is it an original?
We let out a deep sigh
And the oceans responded to us
What is this song?
With a big white wave
Aw, I wanted the usual stuff.
And dragged the wind away with it
This doesn't feel like her.
I don't know, I think I like this better.
After we saw it off
We made a promise for no reason
Yeah...
The calm takes over the night
When the calm takes over the night
We feel like there's nobody else
in the world but us
The sea blends into the sky
When the sea quietly blends into the sky
I know it's just the two of us
But I still whisper to you
When did she write a song like this?
Ah, in the calm of night
What's more, she did it all on her own,
without yours truly's help?
Rikka!
When did you write that original song?
It's really good!
It seems I've underestimated you!
You've grown a lot when I wasn't looking!
Seriously.
You haven't given me
enough attention lately.
Uh...
For this song, I stopped caring
about appealing to everyone.
I wrote it for someone special to me—
my best friend,
and one more throw-in.
I'm a throw-in, huh?
WHILE YOU LOOK AWAY
We have a date and time
for the street performance!
I've secured a venue, too.
Now we just need your songs.
Now, rock my inner ear
with the power of your new songs!
Shut up!
Rikka's working on a song right now.
My bad.
And Bucky, your regular voice
is already loud enough.
Didn't you say you were done?
There's still one left.
I'm planning to put five songs on the CD
I'm selling at the performance.
But I just can't finish the last song.
Considering how you couldn't write
at all before, this is good progress.
You're doing well.
Hey! Don't throw
my praise out the window!
Rikka ain't an easy lass.
Oh, I finished the draft for my CD cover.
Show us! Show us!
What do you think?
Do you hate rabbits?
That's a peace sign, not a rabbit.
So, what does this mean?
Well...
This is a symbol for defiance.
I'll make sure it spreads
to all corners of Japan.
Huh...
Wow. Now even I'm starting to get nervous.
We'll all come watch your show, okay?
Oh, about that...
For this show,
I'd like to do it without your help.
Huh?
Having you there would make me
happy and help me relax,
but if I got too used to that,
there'd be no point to this show.
I see.
That's a shame, but I guess
it's for your own good.
Okay, gotcha.
But we'll be at the next show, okay?
By the way...
How'd you suddenly make progress
after being stuck for so long?
Did you find a song-writing trick
or something?
Trick? Hmm...
All this time, I'd been trying to write
songs that'd appeal to lots of people.
Songs I wouldn't be ashamed of,
songs that would actually sell.
That's what I was trying to do,
but it just didn't go well.
When I tried writing them while picturing
the person I'm dedicating them to,
the lyrics and melodies
came naturally to me.
Come to think of it, I wasn't making
music to send some kind of message.
I was making music because I wanted
this person to listen to my songs.
But my pen stopped moving
while writing this last song.
Why?
If I want to say something,
maybe I should tell them directly
instead of using my music.
I see. She's reached an impasse.
As a producer, I should resolve this
and have her write the best song ever.
Rikka.
Is there anything I can do for you?
I can get you anything you desire,
be it a place, a situation, or people.
Ugh, you sound like a scrub
who got rich.
Anything? Really?
Of course! For yours truly,
impossible is nothing!
In that case...
Yamabuki-kun, over here.
I did say I could get you anything...
But why ask to chat with me
by the beach at night?
I used to write songs
at midnight just like this.
I thought being here might help.
Have a little chat with me.
Come sit next to me.
About what you said earlier today...
"Making music for just one person."
That's a good way to go about it.
For example, Beethoven supposedly
dedicated "Für Elise" to someone he loved,
and it's still beloved
200 years later.
It's amazing that you discovered
this method all on your own.
Great job, Rikka.
So...
Who are you dedicating those songs to?
Huh? I'm too embarrassed to say.
Let's just say it's someone I once
distanced myself from out of awkwardness,
and now I need to work up the courage
to tell them how I feel, maybe?
I see.
She must be talking about
her friend, that Aiko girl.
They did have a falling out
over musical styles.
And?
What are you trying to tell
this person through your music?
You want me to tell you here?
I won't know unless you tell me.
"I love you."
That's rather direct, but she wants
to convey her love for her friend, huh?
What's wrong? Are you feeling unwell?
Not really.
Hey, Rikka.
Can I take a look at your lyrics?
What?!
Or I won't know anything.
Yeah, but...
How's getting embarrassed going to help?
Here.
Okay.
I see.
Hmm, are you being evasive on purpose?
These lyrics are pretty abstract
and avoid expressing anything directly.
They won't get the message.
What exactly do you love about them?
Huh?!
Er...
Well, uh... they were a good listener
to me late at night...
and encouraged me to pursue my dream.
I really enjoyed talking to them,
and they gave me hope.
What else? Give me more.
Urk...
Th-They're kind...
Yes, and?
They have a pleasant voice.
Keep going!
But the biggest thing...
is that they waited for me all this time
after I ran away from them.
What a thoughtful person!
See? You've got all these things to say.
Why not use your lyrics to do it?
It feels like cheating to use music
to express what I couldn't say directly.
If I express my feelings that way,
it might disappoint them.
I feel like they'd want to hear what
they really want to hear directly from me.
Rikka.
What?
You...
Little Miss Want-It-All!
Huh?
You are blessed with a gift!
You can express yourself
in a way most people can't!
What's there to debate?!
There's no hierarchy in self-expression!
It's not the method—it's the strength
of feeling that moves the heart.
Not using a gift you have goes against
the Yamabukis' way of life!
I'm an Inohana, though? Let's say...
Let's say someone used a song
to express their feelings to you.
Would you be happy?
Yes.
Very happy.
I see.
Then I guess I'll leave
this song off the CD.
What? I thought I just
got rid of your worries!
It's because this last song is meant
to express something very dear to me.
Once I can call myself an artist—
once I feel I have the right to use
music as a means of expression—
only then will I release it to the world.
Are you going to save it
for a Budokan concert?
Nothing that grand.
If this street performance goes well
and I manage to sell 50 copies of my CD,
then...
I'll sing it to the person dear to me.
I'm performing here?
Indeed. This park is known as
a mecca for street performances.
Celestial, the latest-and-hottest
band right now,
performed here
until last year too, I hear.
So the audience will have
pretty high standards.
But if you can pick up fans here,
you'll surely make a name for yourself.
I made fliers and distributed them.
You need to make a good first
impression to win the audience over.
I secured you a spot with
plenty of space and visibility.
I'm getting a sharp pain in my chest.
This brings back memories.
I was nervous the first time, too.
But...
It's a different kind of pain now.
Back then, I knew nothing
and was full of wide-eyed hope,
but now I'm just scared.
Scared they'll look at me
with those eyes again.
What now?
I probably can't do this.
Maybe I should just call it off,
or something...
Rikka.
Wh-What?
Do you find my eyes scary?
N-Not really?
Right? Aren't they lovely?
Don't put words in my mouth.
Listen, Rikka.
If you're having a hard time during
the show and can't keep your head up,
just look into my eyes.
O-Okay.
Great.
It's a good thing I came prepared.
Even if you lose sight of me
among a sea of spectators,
you'll be able to see me wave these!
I'd die of cringe, so don't you dare.
What? You'd use the word "cringe"
to describe yours truly?!
You're helping me loosen up, huh? Thanks.
I'll give it a shot.
Yeah, do your best.
We'll watch over you the whole time.
500 YEN PER CD
INOHANA RIKKA
Here I go with my first song,
"Flickering Days."
As we looked up the open blue sky
What do you... wanna do now?
In bright white letters
We wrote about our purpose,
we wrote about our future
And painted it with our dreams
With each passing "See you tomorrow"
Her voice lacks its usual oomph,
and she's not in the right rhythm.
I suppose it's not that easy
to get rid of her anxiety.
Our hearts grew closer
As we have good times and bad
With no audience, her
mental state will only worsen.
We walk in awkward strides
You need to stay calm, Rikka.
We hold hands tight,
and our words reach each other
I knew it wouldn't work.
Nobody's stopping.
And gently push us forward
Nobody's listening to my song.
The round postbox, the usual crosswalk
I thought you'd be up for it.
That teary face, the shining smile
They're all de—
Maybe I expected too much of you.
Sorry, Aiko. I just can't...
Rikka.
H-Huh? We got lost and wound up here...
Your acting's way too awkward!
C-Come on!
We don't want to miss our train!
Imagine we're always in the front row.
Right, I'd forgotten.
Screw trying to sing for lots of people.
I'll just sing for the people
I want to hear my song.
Here's my second song,
"ask for the moon."
I wrote this song for my three
fellow broadcasting club members.
So they're the only people
I need to sing for.
I believe these hands, my voice
Will get to where I want them to go
380,000 kilometers
From an impossible distance
I made the right call by asking
for their help.
BROADCASTING ROOM (TEMP)
You steal my heart away
What? She's lying?
And shine a light on my solitude
Yes. She said not to come because she
didn't want to be overly reliant on you,
Whether it was coincidence
or a magic spell
but that's not all.
She doesn't want you to see her fail.
The clouds give way to a ray of hope
She's scared that you might look at her
with disappointment in your eyes.
We'd never look at her
that way, you dumbass!
Is it possible or impossible
Yeah, never!
Will it come true or not
Why get mad at me?
What can we do, then?
Nobody knows
You don't have to watch her show up close.
That's why I hope, that's why I journey
Just be there for Rikka.
Using my dreams as footholds
She's getting better and better.
Keep it up and reel them in!
I know your voice can reach them, Rikka!
Wanting to touch the waxing
and waning moon
I reached out
Even if it was a small,
insignificant step
I traveled my universe
Believing I'll get there someday
That girl has a lovely voice.
Even if I must walk down
a path never trodden before
Want to stay and listen?
Even if I'm dreaming too big,
hoping for too much
My hand traverses
a 60-centimeter universe
And gets closer to
the bright side of the moon
Watch me
See?
TRANSLATION: SRIRAM GURUNATHAN
TIMING: MARIANA MARTINEZ
EDITING: WILLIAM HAGGARD
QUALITY CHECK: S BILYEU
TRANSLATION CHECK: MICHELLE TYMON